SARUTOBI ASUMA
Asuma...
(カカシ)アスマ…。
(木ノ葉丸)うっ… アスマ叔父ちゃん。
Uncle Asuma...
Where is Shikamaru?
(いの)シカマルは？
(チョウジ)もう出かけたって➡
I thought my mom said
that he left already...
おばちゃん 言ってたのに。
Hey, I told you not to play
on the roof!
コラッ！ 屋根に上がって
遊んじゃダメって➡
いつも 言ってるでしょ！
ごめんなさい。
- Yes.
- I'm sorry.
(シカマル)ハハッ。
BARBE-Q
あぁ シカマル！
Oh, Shikamaru!
(シカマル)あぁ どうも。
最近 ごぶさたやね～。
Oh hello.
I haven't seen you in a while,
have you been busy?
忙しいん？
あぁ… まぁ。
Yeah.
また寄ってな。
Come by again.
Say "Hi" to Asuma Sensei
and Choji for me.
アスマ先生や チョウジ君にも
よろしゅうね。
あっ…。
そうや！ 先生には➡
Oh yeah, I have to ask Sensei
to pay off his balance.
たまったツケも
返してもらわんとな。 アハハハ！
Um... Asuma is...
あ あの… アスマは…。
うん？
Huh?
殉職しました。
He died in duty.
じゃあ… 昨日
死んだって言ってたの…。
Then, so the one that died yesterday...
そんな…。
This can't be...
(シカマルの母)シカマル…
そろそろ夕食を…。
Shikamaru...
It's almost dinner...
(シカマル)いいや… 食欲ねえんだ。
It's okay. I don't feel like eating.
(シカク)シカマル… 少し つき合え。
Shikamaru.
Come with me for a sec.
(シカク)今日は やけに雑だな。
You're pretty forceful today.
それじゃ勝てんぞ。
うるせぇよ。
You can't win that way.
Shut up.
暁か… ヤツら 強いか？
あぁ。
Akatsuki, huh?
Are they...strong?
Yeah.
で どうするんだ。
So, what are you going to do?
アスマほどの男が かなわないなら
お前など 歯がたたんか。
If Asuma couldn't beat them,
then you won't be able to do anything.
本当に いいヤツだったな。
あぁ。
He was a really good guy.
Yeah.
将棋は弱かったが…。
He sucked at Shogi, though.
それで いいのか？
Are you sure about that?
人の打ち筋に ケチつけんなよ。
Don't mess with my move.
違う。 お前は どうしたいんだ。
Not that. What do you want to do?
まぁ みすみす死ににいくほど
バカじゃないか。
Well, I guess you're not stupid
enough to go die.
親としても ありがたいしな。
As a parent,
that is very fortunate that.
息子の葬式なんざ ごめんだ。
Who wants to go to
their son's funeral?
お前は よくやってるよ。
親としても鼻が高いぞ。
You are doing well.
I am proud to be your parent.
頭も切れるし 才能もある。
木ノ葉の将来を担える器だ。
You're sharp, and you're talented.
You are capable of taking on
the future of Hidden Leaf Village.
だが… アスマは死んだ。
But...
Asuma died.
(シカマル)何が言いたいんだよ？
What are you trying to say?
本心だ。
The truth.
(シカマル)気色 悪いんだよ!!
アンタが そんなベラベラしゃべんの！
It's repulsive that
you're talking so much!
どうせ オレは
役立たずの臆病もんだよ！
Yes, I am just a useless coward!
いや。
(シカマル)じゃあ 何なんだよ！
No.
Then what?!
さらけ出しちまえ。
Just let it all out.
悲しみも 恐れも 憤りも…。
Let out all your sadness,
fears, and anger...
何もかも
腹ん中全部 吐き出しちまえ。
and everything else!
そして それからだ。
And it all starts from there...
(シカマル)うわ～っ！
骨は 拾ってやるぞ。
I'll pick up your pieces...
(シカマル)うわ～っ…。
フン。
HIDDEN LEAF LIBRARY
ちわ～す。
Hello!
Hey!
(チョウジの母)あ… シカマル！
Shikamaru!
(シカマル)どうも。
(チョウジの母)大変だったね…。
Hello...
It must have been hard to
deal with what happened to Asuma...
アスマが あんなことに…。
もう… なんて言っていいのか…。
あの子も そりゃ悲しんで…。
I don't know what to say...
Choji is also...
Shikamaru.
(チョウザ)シカマル。
You...
あなた…。
チョウジに 用なんだろ？
You want to see Choji, right?
(チョウザ)アイツなら 裏山にいるぞ。
He's by the hill in the back.
へぇ…。
Sheesh!
(シカマル)また ずいぶんと
深く えぐってんな。
Looks like you dug deep.
Huh?! Shikamaru!
あ… シカマル！
ハハ… おばさんから これ
預かってきたぜ！
Your mom told me to give you this.
So, when?
で いつ？
やるんだろう？
ボク 何すればいい？
You are gonna do it, right?!
What should I do?
Umm...are you telling me...
うん？ えぇ～っ まさか ボクは…。
フッ なら早速
ひと仕事 頼めるかな？
Then, can I ask you to
do something for me?
はっ …うん！
Yeah!
YAMANAKA FLOWERS
シカマル！ やるのね！
Shikamaru!
You're gonna do it right?!
SARUTOBI ASUMA
ありがとうな。
Thank you.
顔出すの 遅れてすまねえ。
Sorry I'm late...
でも もう 迷うの やめたよ。
But I won't hesitate anymore.
オレら すっげぇ ムチャなこと➡
We might be trying to do
something really risky...
しようとしてるかもしんねえけど
見守っていてくれよな。
Please look after us...
…アスマ先生。
Asuma Sensei...
アスマ… 先生。
Asuma...Sensei.
準備できた？
Are you ready?
いくよ！ シカマル。
Let's go, Shikamaru.
あぁ。
Yeah.
(綱手)待て！
Wait!
(いの)五代目様…。
(綱手)どこへ行く気だ？
Lady Fifth Hokage...
Where are you going?
(シカマル)
任務命令は 継続中ですよね？
The mission order is still on right?
オレらは 新しく班を編成して
これから 任務に向かいます。
We formed a new team and
we are going to execute the mission.
身勝手な行動は 許さん！
I will not allow selfish actions!
シカマル。 お前は➡
Shikamaru, I will have you
join the new unit I form.
こちらで再編成した小隊に
組み込む。
そして しっかりとしたプランを
立ててから 行かせる。
Then, I will have you go after
we come up with a solid plan.
あとで 増援を送ってくれれば
いいっすよ。
Just send some support later.
オレらの連携で すでに
作戦も立ててありますから。
Our team has already come up
with a plan.
いいかげんにしろ！
Enough!
アスマは死んだ。
今のお前らは ３人きりだ。
Asuma is dead.
There are only three of you now.
アスマは オレたちと共にいる。
Asuma is with us.
弔い合戦でも するつもりか？
Are you planning to avenge him
in this battle?
お前らしくもない。
犬死にしたいのか？
It's not like you.
Do you want to die in vain?!
オレたちだって バカじゃないっすよ。
We are not that stupid.
I have no intention to die...
死ににいくつもりなんて
毛頭ないっすから。 ただ…。
But...
ただ… なんだ？
But...what?
このまま逃げて 筋を通さねえまま
生きていくような➡
I don't want to give up without
setting things straight...
そういう 面倒くせぇ生き方➡
I don't want to live
a crappy life like that.
したくねえんすよ。
成長しろ。
Grow up...
忍には 死がついてまわる。
Death always haunts Ninja...
(綱手)ときには
受け入れがたい死もある。
There are times when
you can't accept a death.
しかし それを乗り越えなければ
未来はない。
But, if you do not overcome it,
then there is no future!
(シカマル)この形見のライター…
これ 持ってっと➡
This keepsake lighter.
When I have this, it's as if
Asuma Sensei is nearby...
アスマ先生が近くにいるような
オレらを守ってくれてるような➡
It's as if he is protecting us.
It just feels that way.
そんな感じが するんすよ。
この戦いのケジメがつくまでは
このライターとも一緒だ。
Until this battle comes to an end,
this lighter will always be with us...
現実を見ろ！
お前らは３人しかいない。
Get real.
There are only three of you.
A unit should have four members--!
小隊は…。
４人いれば いいんですよね？
It's fine if there are four, right?
(チョウジ)えっ？
(いの)カカシ先生…。
- Huh?
- Kakashi Sensei?
第十班には
オレが隊長として同行します。
I will join as the captain of Team Ten.
How about that?
それで どうですかね？
カカシ お前…。
Kakashi, you...
止めたところで コイツら
行っちゃいますよ。
Even if you try to stop them,
they're still gonna go.
だったら オレがついていけば
監視役にもなりますし。
But if I go, I can supervise them...
ムチャは させませんから。
I will not allow them to go overboard.
I got it. Do as you like!
わかった 好きにしろ。
All right!
Kakashi Sensei...
How about Naruto?
Your right arm...?
やった！
Forget it, he doesn't need me
at this point.
カカシ先生… ナルトは いいんすか？
Plus, there is another captain
with them.
(いの)その右手…。
Naruto...
Well then, Team Asuma, let's go!
- Right!
- Yes!
I appreciate it, Kakashi Sensei!
(カカシ)な～に… オレはもう
アイツにとっちゃ用済みだ。
まっ それに今は
別の隊長も ついてるしな。
フンッ… ナルトのヤツ。
それじゃ アスマ班 行きますか。
(シカマル)感謝するぜ カカシ先生。